Welcome. In the last lecture, we successfully added in the floor check. Now, when the character
欢迎。在上一次讲座中，我们成功地加入了楼层检查。现在，当角色
has reached the floor during climbing, we'll be exiting the climb state automatically.
到达地面时，我们将自动退出攀爬状态。
And now, our character can climb up, down, left, and right.
现在，我们的角色可以向上、向下、向左和向右爬。
And the next thing that I want to add in is, when our character has reached the ledge,
接下来我想加入的是，当我们的角色到达窗台时、
I want to exit the climb state and climb up the ledge automatically. And in this lecture,
我想退出攀爬状态并自动爬上壁架。在这个讲座中
we'll look at how we can implement this. And let's first try to narrow down what we
我们将研究如何实现这一功能。首先让我们试着缩小我们的范围
want to do in here. So basically, we need to do two things. First, we'll need to detect
想在这里做什么。所以基本上，我们需要做两件事。首先，我们需要检测
the ledge during climbing. And if we have indeed reached one, we need to play the ledge
攀登过程中的壁架。而如果我们确实已经到达了一个，我们需要播放壁架
climb animation. This part here is actually a bit trickier than it sounds because of the
攀爬动画。这一部分实际上比听起来要棘手一些，因为我们使用的是
animation assets that we are using. We'll know why very soon. For now, let's just take
我们正在使用的动画资产。我们很快就会知道原因。现在，让我们只处理
care of the first part. And this is how I want to approach it. I'm going to use two
处理第一部分。这就是我想要的方法。我将使用两个
line traces to detect the ledge. During climbing, I want to draw the first line trace. And if
线迹来检测壁架。在攀爬过程中，我想画出第一条线迹。而如果
the first line trace does not have a valid hit, then I'm going to draw the second line
第一条线的轨迹没有有效的命中，那么我将绘制第二条线的轨迹
trace. And if the second line trace indeed has a valid hit, then that means we have reached
轨迹。如果第二条线的轨迹确实有一个有效的命中，那么这意味着我们已经达到了
the ledge. So the first line trace here is for detecting if there's a climbable surface
壁垒。所以这里的第一条线迹是用来检测是否有一个可攀登的表面
above the character. And if there's not, the second line trace is for detecting if the
上面是否有可攀登的表面。如果没有，第二行跟踪是为了检测该表面是否
surface is walkable. Again, depending on the geometry and your level, you can perform all
表面是否可以行走。同样，根据几何形状和你的关卡，你可以在这里进行各种检查来决定
sorts of checks in here to decide if the surface is walkable. You have all the math knowledge
你可以在这里进行各种检查来决定这个表面是否可以行走。你有所有的数学知识
you need. So now we need to figure out how to draw these two line traces. And there'll
你需要的所有数学知识。所以现在我们需要弄清楚如何画出这两条线的痕迹。今天会有
be a coding challenge today. So the challenge is I'd like you to use two line traces to
今天有一个编码挑战。这个挑战是我想让你用两条线的轨迹来
detect the ledge. And if you succeed, I'd like you to put a message to the screen if
探测壁架。如果你成功了，我希望你能在屏幕上显示一条信息，如果
the character has reached the ledge. To better prepare you for the challenge, I got some hints
角色已经到达窗台。为了让你更好地迎接挑战，我有一些提示
for you. So you'll find the function that we created i-hightrace and the hit result
暗示给你。所以你会发现我们创建的函数i-hightrace和命中结果
dot trace n very useful. Alright, pause the video now and give this a go. And I'll see
dot trace n非常有用。好了，现在暂停视频，试试这个吧。我将在
you in the solution video.
你在解决方案的视频中见。
[music]
[音乐]